A Guide to the Markle Foundation records, Record Group 1-Record Group 3 FA024
Rockefeller Archive Center
Markle Foundation records, Record Group 1-Record Group 3
1884-1994
1960-1994
Rockefeller Archive Center
Markle, John
Markle, Mary
John and Mary R. Markle Foundation
FA024
116.99 Cubic Feet
Arrangement note
This collection, received in two accessions, is arranged as folows:
Record Group 1 - Markle Foundation Programs Subgroup 1.1: Accession 1 Subgroup 1.2: Accession 2
Record Group 2 - Markle Foundation Administration Subgroup 2.1: Accession 1 Subgroup 2.2: Accession 2
Record Group 3 - John Markle Personal Material
Series 1064 - Photographs
Biographical/Historical note
John Markle was born in Hazelton, Pennsylvania, in 1858. He graduated from Lafayette College in 1880 with a degree in mining engineering and soon took charge of the firm his father had founded, G. B. Markle and Company, which operated the Jeddo mine. Markle was a successful businessman who became known nationally as the builder of the Jeddo drainage tunnel, which reclaimed Pennsylvania mines inundated by floods in 1886. In April 1884, Markle married Mary Estelle Robinson (1863-1927). The couple moved from Hazelton, Pennsylvania, to New York City in 1902. They had no children. In 1926, John Markle retired from business, and the following year he established the John and Mary R. Markle Foundation with an initial endowment of $3 million. Eventually the total endowment from John Markle reached $15 million. John Markle served as president and treasurer of the Foundation until his death in July 1933. The Foundation was chartered "to promote the advancement and diffusion of knowledge among the people of the United States and to promote the general good of mankind." This charter was sufficiently broad to permit supporting virtually any cause and allowed the directors to spend principal as well as income, which the Foundation did in its early years. (The founder rectified the difference.) Grants, averaging a total of $400,000 annually, went primarily to charities which the Markle family had previously supported. In addition, the Markle Foundation financially supported individuals, including relatives and needy strangers who came to John Markle's attention and in whom he took a personal interest. After John Markle's death, the Foundation trustees sought direction from Frederick Keppel, president of the Carnegie Corporation of New York. Following his advice, the Foundation changed from a private organization to a focused public foundation. There were no new individual beneficiaries after 1934, and the trustees began to formulate a plan of action. From 1936 to 1945, the Markle Foundation primarily supported medical research: 627 grants were made to 336 projects, and 1,400 scientific papers were published regarding work supported wholly or in part by the Foundation. In 1946 John Russell, formerly with the Carnegie Corporation of New York, became the executive director of the Foundation. After making an assessment of the Foundation's work, Russell and the Foundation embarked on an ambitious program - the Markle Scholar Program, which became the principal program of the Markle Foundation from 1947 to 1969. Approximately 25 Markle Scholars were chosen each year. They received five years of financial assistance so that they might continue in academic medicine or research rather than enter more lucrative private practices. A total of 506 Markle Scholars were chosen from 90 medical schools in the United States and Canada. In 1969 John Russell retired, and Lloyd Morrisett, also formerly with the Carnegie Corporation of New York, came to the Foundation. In the last months of Russell's tenure, it had been determined that the Markle Scholar program had run its course, and after an evaluation, the Foundation embarked on an ambitious program in the field of mass communications. Beginning in 1969, the Markle Foundation's program aimed to strengthen the performance of the media and to understand the potential of communications technology. Mass communications and information technology had not been a traditional focus of philanthropy, and the grants reflect challenge and innovation. Disbursements averaged $2 million annually.
Scope and Contents note
Includes grant files, administrative files, correspondence, reports, minutes, financial material, annual reports and a small selection of personal materials. The collection is not comprehensive. Due to routine file purges, this collection includes only the records of the final personal beneficiaries, Markle Scholars, and the communications program, along with assorted administrative files. Documentation of other grants exist only in the minutes, progress reports, and collected reprints.
When John Markle moved the base of his business operations from Hazelton, Pennsylvania to New York City in 1902, he periodically returned to Hazelton and destroyed his records. Records remaining in Pennsylvania at the time of his death in 1933 were shipped to his executors in New York City. The executors (and the Foundation) retained only those records directly affecting the finances of Markle's estate.
File Plan note
Former Classification: XI
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. In addition separated media may not yet have undergone stabilization procedures. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The John and Mary R. Markle Foundation gave its records to the Rockefeller Archive Center in two accessions: one in 1993, and another in 1997.
Philanthropy -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations; Public health; Medical education; Philanthropy; Medical research; United States; Charities
- Markle Foundation Programs, 1
  Arrangement
  This record group is arranged into two subgroups:
  Subgroup 1 - Markle Foundation Programs - Accession 1
  Subgroup 2 - Markle Foundation Programs - Accession 2
  - Markle Foundation Programs - Accession 1, 1; 41 Cubic Feet
    Arrangement note
    This subgroup is arranged in three series:
    Series 1 - Beneficiaries
    Series 2 - Markle Scholars
    Series 3 - Communications
    - Beneficiaries, 1935-1972; 1; 2.2 Cubic Feet 5 boxes
      This series is arranged in two subseries:
      Subseries 1 - Administration
      Subseries 2 - Individual Beneficiaries
      Scope and Contents note
      This series includes files concerning the administration of the program and files on individual beneficiaries.
      - Administration, 1935-1950; 1
        - General, 1939-1949, 1962-1963, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - Audits, 1935, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - Brunot & Quick Reports, 1935-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - "Preliminary Progress Reports", March 2, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - "Report on Survey", May 22, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - "Personal Beneficiary Program - Individual Beneficiary Reports", May 22, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Individual Beneficiaries, 1929-1972; 2
        - Deceased (A-D), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 7)
        - Deceased (G-H), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 8)
        - Deceased (I-L), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)
        - Deceased (M-P), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 10)
        - Deceased (R), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11)
        - Deceased (S-Th), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12)
        - Deceased (Ti-V), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 13)
        - Discontinued (A-Z), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 14)
        - Joseph Alexander, 1935-1963 (Box 3, Folder 15)
        - Marietta Barber, 1932-1965 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        - Maude H. Barber, 1933-1969 (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - Clara Bates, 1940-1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
        - Rosa Barto, 1927-1965 (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - Evangeline Booth, 1942-1947 (Box 3, Folder 20)
        - Frederick Butzberger, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 21)
        - Vida Barton Ellis, 1928-1933 (Box 3, Folder 22)
        - Vida Barton Ellis, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 23)
        - Children of Vida Barton Ellis, 1935-1942 (Box 4, Folder 24)
        - Children of Vida Barton Ellis, 1942-1947 (Box 4, Folder 25)
        - Carolyn Follmer, 1927-1963 (Box 4, Folder 26)
        - Mae Griffin, 1931-1965 (Box 4, Folder 27)
        - Florence Hinck, 1949-1972 (Box 4, Folder 28)
        - May Hollanhan, 1934-1968 (Box 4, Folder 29)
        - Estella Howells, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 30)
        - Eleanor Judd, 1929-1954 (Box 4, Folder 31)
        - Miriam Kirkwood, 1930-1935 (Box 4, Folder 32)
        - Olaf Larsen, 1931-1966 (Box 5, Folder 33)
        - Clara Maneval, 1927-1968 (Box 5, Folder 34)
        - Frank Miller, 1938-1968 (Box 5, Folder 35)
        - Esther E. Moffatt, 1941-1966 (Box 5, Folder 36)
        - Helen Peck, 1933-1969 (Box 5, Folder 37)
        - Nellie Peet, 1933-1965 (Box 5, Folder 38)
        - Mrs. A. H. Robison, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 39)
        - Irwin Robison (Esther), 1933-1969 (Box 5, Folder 40)
        - Isiah Robison (Helen), 1932-1946 (Box 5, Folder 41)
        - J. Norris Robison, 1934-1957 (Box 5, Folder 42)
        - James B. Robison (Lillian), 1939-1950 (Box 5, Folder 43)
        - John B. and Irvin A. Robison, 1939-1950 (Box 5, Folder 44)
        - Edward Rogers (Grace), 1934-1969 (Box 5, Folder 45)
        - Edith Vail, 1933-1969 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Markle Scholars, 1937-1971; 2; 8.8 Cubic Feet 20 boxes
      This series is arranged in five subseries:
      Subseries 1 - Regional Meetings
      Subseries 2 - Candidate Data
      Subseries 3 - Scholar Files
      Subseries 4 - Administration
      Subseries 5 - Markle Scholar Association
      - Regional Meetings, 1948-1969; 1
        Subseries 1 includes the minutes of the regional committee meetings.
        - Minutes, 1948-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - Minutes, 1956-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - Minutes, 1962-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Candidate Data, 1948-1969; 2
        - 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        - 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        - 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        - 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
        - 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
        - 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
        - 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 14)
        - 1969 (Box 3, Folder 15)
        - Summary of Scholars, 1948-1959 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        - Presentation to Markle Foundation Board of Trustees (Barker - Gershon), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - Presentation to Markle Foundation Board of Trustees (Glazer - Parker), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
        - Presentation to Markle Foundation Board of Trustees (Pfieffer - Wilson), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Scholar Files, 1960-1969; 3
        Scholar files are arranged alphabetically by institution. If the scholar changed institutions during his time as a Markle Scholar, the material was filed by the new institution.
        Scholar file correspondence is more personal and administrative than scientific in nature.
        - Medical College of Alabama - J. Claude Bennett, 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 20)
        - Medical College of Alabama - William Harlan Jr., 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 21)
        - Medical College of Alabama - Clifton K. Meador, 1963-1969 (Box 4, Folder 22)
        - Medical College of Alabama - David B. Ludlum, 1967-1986 (Box 4, Folder 23)
        - University of Arizona - Vincent Fulginiti, 1964-1969 (Box 4, Folder 24)
        - University of Arizona - Frank I. Marcus, 1960-1968 (Box 4, Folder 25)
        - Baylor College of Medicine - Robert J. Luchi, 1963-1969 (Box 4, Folder 26)
        - Baylor College of Medicine - David Paton, 1967-1973 (Box 4, Folder 27)
        - Baylor College of Medicine - F. Brantley Scott Jr., 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 28)
        - Boston University - John A. Mannick, 1961-1966 (Box 4, Folder 29)
        - Boston University - Donald Small, 1966-1971 (Box 4, Folder 30)
        - Bowman Gray School of Medicine - Richard Janeway, 1969-1973 (Box 4, Folder 31)
        - Bowman Gray School of Medicine - Joseph E. Johnson, 1961-1973 (Box 4, Folder 32)
        - Bowman Gray School of Medicine - Lawrence C. McHenry Jr., 1967-1973 (Box 4, Folder 33)
        - Bowman Gray School of Medicine - Richard B. Patterson, 1962-1967 (Box 4, Folder 34)
        - University of British Columbia - Alexander R. M. Cairns, 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 35)
        - University of British Columbia - Joseph A. Hinke, 1959-1965 (Box 5, Folder 36)
        - University of British Columbia - John A. Birkbeck, 1964-1969 (Box 5, Folder 37)
        - University of British Columbia - William E. Shepherd, 1961-1965 (Box 5, Folder 38)
        - University of British Columbia - Roger Tonkin, 1969-1974 (Box 5, Folder 39)
        - University of Calgary - Keith L. MacCannell, 1966-1971 (Box 5, Folder 40)
        - University of California, Irvine - Hubert Pirkle, 1960-1966 (Box 5, Folder 41)
        - University of California, Los Angeles - Eric V. Fonkalsrud, 1963-1968 (Box 5, Folder 42)
        - University of California, Los Angeles - Joram Heller, 1969-1974 (Box 5, Folder 43)
        - University of California, Los Angeles - David Maxwell, 1959-1965 (Box 5, Folder 44)
        - University of California, Los Angeles - E. Richard Stiehm, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 45)
        - University of California, Los Angeles - Richard Young, 1962-1968 (Box 5, Folder 46)
        - University of California, San Diego - Eugene F. Bernstein, 1963-1970 (Box 5, Folder 47)
        - University of California, San Diego - Darrell Fanestil, 1966-1971 (Box 5, Folder 48)
        - University of California, San Diego - Paul Friedman, 1969-1974 (Box 5, Folder 49)
        - University of California, San Diego - Nickolas Halasz, 1964-1969 (Box 5, Folder 50)
        - University of California, San Francisco - Robert A. Fishman, 1960-1968 (Box 6, Folder 51)
        - University of California, San Francisco - Bertram Katzung, 1966-1973 (Box 6, Folder 52)
        - University of California, San Francisco - William Tooley, 1963-1968 (Box 6, Folder 53)
        - University of California, San Francisco - Hibbard Williams, 1968-1974 (Box 6, Folder 54)
        - Case Western Reserve University - Thomas Daniel, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 55)
          Related Archival Materials note
          See also Western Reserve University
        - Case Western Reserve University - Robert Kellermeyer, 1965-1970 (Box 6, Folder 56)
        - Case Western Reserve University - Thomas Moir, 1962-1969 (Box 6, Folder 57)
        - Case Western Reserve University - Thomas Teree, 1964-1973 (Box 6, Folder 58)
        - University of Chicago - Frank Fitch, 1961-1966 (Box 6, Folder 59)
        - University of Chicago - Ann Lawrence, 1967-1975 (Box 6, Folder 60)
        - University of Chicago - Daniel McCarthy, 1962-1974 (Box 6, Folder 61)
        - University of Chicago - Robert Moore, 1965-1970 (Box 6, Folder 62)
        - University of Chicago - David Skinner, 1969-1974 (Box 6, Folder 63)
        - University of Chicago - Frank Stuart, 1969-1975 (Box 6, Folder 64)
        - University of Chicago - Alvin Tarlov, 1966-1972 (Box 6, Folder 65)
        - University of Chicago - Stanley Yachnin, 1963-1969 (Box 7, Folder 66)
        - University of Chicago - Harvey Zarem, 1967-1972 (Box 7, Folder 67)
        - Columbia University - Michael Gershon, 1968-1977 (Box 7, Folder 68)
        - Columbia University - Ann Peterson, 1965-1977 (Box 7, Folder 69)
        - Cornell University - Dana Brooks, 1961-1969 (Box 7, Folder 70)
        - Cornell University - Paul Ebert, 1967-1973 (Box 7, Folder 71)
        - Cornell University - Thomas Meikle Jr., 1963-1969 (Box 7, Folder 72)
        - Cornell University - Charles Santos-Buch, 1964-1970 (Box 7, Folder 73)
        - Creighton University - W. Eugene Sanders Jr., 1968-1973 (Box 7, Folder 74)
        - Dalhousie University - C. Edwin Kinley, 1964-1969 (Box 7, Folder 75)
        - Dalhousie University - George Langley, 1963-1968 (Box 7, Folder 76)
        - Dartmouth Medical School - Michael Galton, 1963-1969 (Box 7, Folder 77)
        - Dartmouth Medical School - O. Ross McIntyre, 1965-1971 (Box 7, Folder 78)
        - Dartmouth Medical School - John Remmers, 1969-1974 (Box 7, Folder 79)
        - Duke University - Nicholas Kredich, 1969-1974 (Box 7, Folder 80)
        - Duke University - Delford Stickel, 1962-1967 (Box 8, Folder 81)
        - Duke University - Andrew Wallace, 1965-1974 (Box 8, Folder 82)
        - Emory University - Ellis Keener, 1961-1964 (Box 8, Folder 83)
        - University of Florida - Lamar Crevasse Jr., 1960-1967 (Box 8, Folder 84)
        - George Washington University - Thomas Piemme, 1966-1971 (Box 8, Folder 85)
        - George Medical College - William Chew, 1964-1969 (Box 8, Folder 86)
        - Harvard Medical School - W. Gerald Austin, 1963-1966 (Box 8, Folder 87)
        - Harvard Medical School - John Blinks, 1961-1968 (Box 8, Folder 88)
        - Harvard Medical School - Raphael Levey, 1969-1974 (Box 8, Folder 89)
        - Harvard Medical School - Lincoln Potter, 1965-1974 (Box 8, Folder 90)
        - Harvard Medical School - Robert Haggerty, 1961-1980 (Box 8, Folder 91)
        - Harvard Medical School - Edwin Salzman, 1968-1972 (Box 8, Folder 92)
        - University of Illinois - Truman Anderson, 1963-1968 (Box 8, Folder 93)
        - University of Illinois - Olga Jonasson, 1969-1974 (Box 8, Folder 94)
        - University of Illinois - John Loesch, 1960-1966 (Box 8, Folder 95)
        - University of Illinois - Richard Marcus, 1951-1954 (Box 8, Folder 96)
        - University of Illinois - Alexander Schmidt, 1966-1971 (Box 8, Folder 97)
        - Indiana University Medical School - Tang-Kai Li, 1967-1973 (Box 9, Folder 98)
        - Indiana University Medical School - Walter Nance, 1963-1968 (Box 9, Folder 99)
        - University of Iowa - James Christensen, 1965-1970 (Box 9, Folder 100)
        - University of Iowa - Edson Forker, 1967-1972 (Box 9, Folder 101)
        - State University of Iowa - James Spratt, 1963-1969 (Box 9, Folder 102)
        - State University of Iowa - Daniel Stone, 1960-1970 (Box 9, Folder 103)
        - State University of Iowa - Daniel Stone, 1960-1970 (Box 9, Folder 104)
        - Jefferson Medical College - Gonzolo Aponte, 1960-1968 (Box 9, Folder 105)
        - Jefferson Medical College - Joseph White, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 106)
        - Jefferson Medical College - Paul Zimskind, 1966-1971 (Box 9, Folder 107)
        - Johns Hopkins University - Mary Ellen Avery, 1961-1968 (Box 9, Folder 108)
        - Johns Hopkins University - Evan Charney, 1968-1975 (Box 9, Folder 109)
        - Johns Hopkins University - Vincent Gott, 1962-1967 (Box 9, Folder 110)
        - Johns Hopkins University - J. Alex Haller Jr., 1961-1969 (Box 9, Folder 111)
        - Johns Hopkins University - Theodore King, 1967-1972 (Box 9, Folder 112)
        - Johns Hopkins University - Jack Levin, 1968-1982 (Box 10, Folder 113)
        - Johns Hopkins University - Guy McKhann, 1964-1971 (Box 10, Folder 114)
        - Johns Hopkins University - Karl Schellenbert, 1965-1970 (Box 10, Folder 115)
        - Johns Hopkins University - George Williams, 1967-1973 (Box 10, Folder 116)
        - Johns Hopkins University - George Zuidema, 1961-1969 (Box 10, Folder 117)
        - University of Kansas - Daniel Azarnoff, 1962-1969 (Box 10, Folder 118)
        - University of Kansas - Lucien Leape, 1968-1973 (Box 10, Folder 119)
        - University of Kansas - Harry White, 1965-1970 (Box 10, Folder 120)
        - University of Kansas - James Warren, 1961-1968 (Box 10, Folder 120A)
        - University of Kentucky - Gordon Danielson, 1962-1967 (Box 10, Folder 121)
        - University of Kentucky - Ward Griffin, 1962-1967 (Box 10, Folder 122)
        - Laval University - Guy Saucier, 1962-1967 (Box 10, Folder 123)
        - Laval University - Yves Warren, 1967-1973 (Box 10, Folder 124)
        - University of Louisiana - William Blackard, 1968-1973 (Box 10, Folder 125)
        - University of Louisville - Allan Lansing, 1961-1969 (Box 10, Folder 126)
        - Loyola University - Clarence Peiss, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 127)
        - University of Manitoba - James Lind, 1960-1966 (Box 10, Folder 128)
        - University of Marquette - Sidney Grossberg, 1966-1970 (Box 10, Folder 129)
        - University of Maryland - Stanford Friedman, 1965-1973 (Box 10, Folder 130)
        - University of Maryland - George Mason, 1969-1981 (Box 11, Folder 131)
        - University of Maryland - Joseph McLaughlin, 1966-1971 (Box 11, Folder 132)
        - McGill University - E. John Hinchey, 1966-1972 (Box 11, Folder 133)
        - McGill University - Gerald Klassen, 1965-1971 (Box 11, Folder 134)
        - McGill University - Charles Shriver, 1961-1968 (Box 11, Folder 135)
        - McGill University - Allan Sherwin, 1962-1967 (Box 11, Folder 136)
        - University of Miami - Carl Goldsmith, 1962-1969 (Box 11, Folder 137)
        - University of Miami - Donald Harkness, 1966-1972 (Box 11, Folder 138)
        - University of Miami - Karl Muench, 1969-1974 (Box 11, Folder 139)
        - University of Miami - William Little, 1962-1969 (Box 11, Folder 140)
        - University of Miami - Roger Palmer, 1965-1972 (Box 11, Folder 141)
        - University of Michigan - Gerald Abrams, 1963-1968 (Box 11, Folder 142)
        - University of Michigan - Robert Carpenter, 1964-1972 (Box 11, Folder 143)
        - University of Michigan - John Gosling, 1960-1972 (Box 11, Folder 144)
        - University of Michigan - Richard Dow, 1967-1973 (Box 11, Folder 145)
        - University of Michigan - Harvey Sparks, 1967-1972 (Box 11, Folder 146)
        - University of Michigan - Arthur Vander, 1965-1970 (Box 12, Folder 147)
        - University of Michigan - Edward Coppola, 1966-1973 (Box 12, Folder 148)
        - University of Minnesota - Richard Lillehei, 1960-1967 (Box 12, Folder 149)
        - University of Minnesota - John Najarian, 1964-1971 (Box 12, Folder 150)
        - University of Minnesota - Paul Quie, 1961-1969 (Box 12, Folder 151)
        - University of Minnesota - Richard Simmons, 1969-1980 (Box 12, Folder 152)
        - University of Mississippi - Norman Nelson, 1965-1974 (Box 12, Folder 153)
        - University of Missouri - Philip Anderson, 1966-1971 (Box 12, Folder 154)
        - University of Missouri - Donald Lindberg, 1964-1969 (Box 12, Folder 155)
        - University of Missouri - William Mayer, 1962-1973 (Box 12, Folder 156)
        - University of Missouri - Charles Mengel, 1963-1969 (Box 12, Folder 157)
        - University of Montreal - Andre Barbereau, 1961-1966 (Box 12, Folder 158)
        - University of Montreal - Jean Davignon, 1966-1972 (Box 13, Folder 159)
        - University of Montreal - Jacques de Champlain, 1968-1973 (Box 13, Folder 160)
        - University of Nebraska - Perry Rigby, 1965-1974 (Box 13, Folder 161)
        - University of Nebraska - Joseph Shipp, 1961-1975 (Box 13, Folder 162)
        - University of Nebraska - William Wilson, 1967-1972 (Box 13, Folder 163)
        - University of New Mexico - Robert Anderson, 1966-1971 (Box 13, Folder 164)
        - University of New Mexico - Raymond Doberneck, 1966-1976 (Box 13, Folder 165)
        - University of New Mexico - Edward Mortimer Jr., 1961-1969 (Box 13, Folder 166)
        - New York Medical College - Thomas Cottrell, 1969-1974 (Box 13, Folder 167)
        - New York State University, Buffalo - Fitzhugh Pannilli Jr., 1962-1974 (Box 13, Folder 168)
        - New York State University, Downstate - Bernard Gardner, 1968-1978 (Box 13, Folder 169)
        - New York State University, Downstate - David Kaplan, 1966-1971 (Box 13, Folder 170)
        - New York State University, Upstate - David Murray, 1965-1970 (Box 13, Folder 171)